

✓ idadesmet@hotmail.com

Q Lonsdale, North Vancouver

in linkedin.com/in/idakdesmet

github.com/idaknow

# IDA DE SMET

## FULL STACK ENGINEER

An enthusiastic and driven software engineer with over 4 years professional experience in start-up environments. In the last two years I transitioned from the data space to a full stack web developer role and have not looked back. I am highly adaptable and a fast learner that is comfortable picking up new tech stacks and taking accountability. I am most proficient in Typescript, React and Python. I am looking to join a company with a lot of growth opportunities.

## EDUCATION

University of Auckland 2014-2019 McGill University, Montreal 2017

- Bachelor of Engineering,
  Software, First Class Honours
- Bachelor of Science, Psychology

### TECH STACK

- Languages: Python, C# .NET,
  TypeScript, JS, HTML, CSS, Bash
- Web: React (Material UI), Vue, GraphQL, REST, Django, Flask
- Database: Postgres, Mongo
- Infrastructure as code: Pulumi
- Cloud: AWS, S3, Azure
- Testing: Cypress, Jest, PyTest
- Log/ Analytics: DataDog, Sentry, Elasticsearch, Graphana, Tableau
- Entry level at: Angular, Golang, Kubernetes, Luigi

# CERTIFIED

- Standard First Aid CPR-C/ AED
- BC Serving It Right

# VOLUNTEER

Mentor, Technovation for girls 2020 Web Admin, Uni Snow Club 2017

# AWARDS

- 2021 Top 1% Ironman 70.3
- 2017 Deans Honours List
- 2013 Rotary Scholarship
- 2012 Olympic Swim Trials

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **FULL STACK ENGINEER @ JOYOUS**

04.2022 - 05.2023

SaaS start-up building an employee feedback platform (Series A US \$10.4M)

- Web developer producing high quality Typescript and React code to support millions of conversations from 100,000+ users in 40+ countries
- Comfortable applying large-scale changes, such as overhauling the logging infrastructure to Datadog by making AWs changes using Pulumi or upgrading node packages to remove 90% of known security concerns
- Deployed integrations with third party applications, such as Microsoft Teams chatbot with proactive installation to 10,000+ users
- Lead the technical analysis, scoping and delivery of projects, such as a campaign insights subset that automated 20% of an analyst's daily tasks
- Wrote technical documentation, such as the BCP plan
- Worked independently or in engineering crews of up to 6 people
- Onboarded and mentored new team members

#### **DATA ENGINEER @ ROCKET LAB**

10.2018 - 03.2022

SpaceX competitor rocket company (US \$4.8 billion at IPO)

- Data processing for 21 flights, 1,000+ engine and 100+ component tests
- Developed a general-purpose Python ETL library, used by over 20 engineers across various teams to time-sync and analyse millions of data points from multiple sources
- Reduced the time of post-flight report generation from hours to minutes
- Active participant in fast-paced, high-priority, R&D work, such as hyper-curie testing for NASA's Mission to the Moon
- Owned and stabilised Propulsion's C# .NET WPF and Python data pipeline to 95% completion, and added end-to-end testing to cover 80% of their use cases
- Angular prototype development and data architecture design
- Agile development and previously scrum master of 8 team members

#### WEB DEVELOPER @ BROWN UNIVERSITY 10.2017 - 03.2019

WebGazer research project to infer gaze location within 100-200 screen pixels

• Implemented <u>calibration</u>, predictability metrics, and a moving average to reduce noise and maintained the open-source project

**SOFTWARE INTERN @ TEKNIQUE** 

10.2016 - 03.2017